Jennifer Trevizo | Full Stack Developer

Houston, TX. | (713)-382-5761 | jennytrevizo18@gmail.com | https://github.com/jtrevz

SUMMARY

Motivated and analytical Full Stack Developer with experience in front-end and back-end programming. Excels at problem-solving and enjoys learning new technologies to enhance skill set. Proficient in several programming languages and tools, including React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, NodeJS, MongoDB, and MySQL. Ability to collaborate effectively and promote a culture of excellence and efficiency that can be an asset to any team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Education

Austin, TX

Full Stack Development Teaching Assistant

January 2022 - Current

- Counseled students learning front and back end programming languages and technologies including: Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, MongoDB, MySQL, Node, Express, GraphQL
- Leveraged my expertise to research and resolve complex technical issues, enabling students to gain a deeper understanding of programming concepts and techniques.
- Provided comprehensive feedback on student code, offering personalized guidance to troubleshoot errors and optimize performance.
- Fostered a culture of excellence and efficiency by promoting best practices and encouraging students to develop their skills through continuous learning and practice.

Savvy Property Group

The Woodlands, TX

Real Estate Agent, Realtor

November 2018 - January 2021

- Worked closely with clients to understand their needs and help them find a home that met their budget and lifestyle requirements
- Negotiated better home loans with lenders and reduced client upfront costs by 15%
- Streamlined loan qualifications, accelerating buying process by up to 2 weeks to better meet client needs

Center for Autism and Related Disorders, LLC.

Austin, TX

Behavioral Analyst, Therapist Trainer

July 2017 - November 2018

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Studious

http://studious-2022.herokuapp.com/| https://github.com/jtrevz/studious

- Developed and deployed a front end web application to help users make and study flashcards
- Utilized React, Javascript, Bootstrap and Firebase

Tripster

https://tripster2021.herokuapp.com/| https://github.com/jtrevz/Tripster

- Led team with development of travel application that allows users to record essential travel information: flight information, itinerary and planned events etc.
- Designed UI layout, developed front end routes, collaborated with database production
- Utilized React, Javascript, Firebase, MongoDB, Express, Node, Bootstrap, Jotai

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp Certificate

Austin, TX

The Coding Bootcamp at the University of Texas

June 2021

St. Edward's University

Austin, TX

Bachelor of Psychology

May 2017

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Soft Skills: Adaptable, Inquisitive, Self-motivated, Problem-Solving Skills, Collaborative

Technical Skills: React, Javascript, Redux, Angular, HTML, CSS, REST APIs, Python, Git, MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, Node, jQuery, Express, Handlebars, MS Office, OOP Programming, Responsive Design, MVC, SCRUM